backerkit.com 2018-12-30

# Privacy Policy | BackerKit

* * *

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which BackerKit collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a "User") of the backerkit.com website ("Site"). This privacy policy applies to the Site and all products and services offered by BackerKit. 

**Personal identification information**  
We may collect personal identification information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our site, register on the site, place an order, subscribe to the newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address, mailing address, credit card information. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities. 

**Non-personal identification information**  
We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information. 

**Web browser cookies**  
Our Site may use "cookies" to enhance User experience. User's web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. User may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If they do so, note that some parts of the Site may not function properly. 

**How we use collected information**  
BackerKit may collect and use Users personal information for the following purposes: 

  * _**To improve customer service**_ Information you provide helps us respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently. 
  * _**To personalize user experience**_ We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Site. 
  * _**To improve our Site**_ We may use feedback you provide to improve our products and services. 
  * _**To process payments**_ We may use the information Users provide about themselves when placing an order only to provide service to that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service. 
  * _**To send periodic emails**_ We may use the email address to send User information and updates pertaining to their order. It may also be used to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email or User may contact us via our Site. 

**Which personal identifying information we collect**  
BackerKit collects personal identifying data in several ways: 

  * _**Backer Data collected when a project syncs via importing backers may include**_  
\- Email address   
\- Address Country   
\- Name   
\- Original platorm ID   
\- Original platform survey answers   

  * _**Backer Data inputted by a Backer may include**_  
\- Answers to survey questions   
\- Email address   
\- Full address information (including phone number for shipping purposes)   

  * _**Data collected via subprocessing tools**_  
\- IP address  
\- Device/browser/session information  
\- URL parameters  

**Sub-processors**  
BackerKit uses several sub-processor to help improve the product. Including tools to help illuminate parts of the website that are are confusing or underused, allowing our product team to improve the customer experience. These tools also help surface errors and allow BackerKit to gain insights into how are users are using the app. These tools also help our Customer Success and Backer Support teams provide support and guidance to creators and backers. Our sub-processors have access to a restricted set of information in order to render the service provided. 

_**List of sub-processor:**_  

  * **Application Hosting:**
    * Amazon Web Services
    * Heroku 
      * as Database Provider
      * as Web Host
      * as Worker Host
  * **via Heroku Plugins:**
    * Librato - Development (logging)
    * Papertrail - Liatorp (logging)
    * Redis Cloud
    * Heroku Scheduler
  * **Operations:**
    * HoneyBadger
    * New Relic
  * **Analytics and referral tracking:**
    * Facebook
    * Google Analytics
    * Perfect Audience
  * **Product Research and development:**
    * LogRocket
    * Optimizely
  * **Messaging:**
    * Mailchimp
    * Mailgun
  * **Payments:**
    * PayPal
    * Stripe
  * **CRM:**
    * Salesforce
  * **Shipping:**
    * Address Validation 
      * SmartyStreets
      * EasyPost
  * **Support Dashboards:**
    * Helpscout
    * Front
  * **Sharing:**
    * Twitter
    * Facebook

**How we protect your information**  
We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site. In the event of data breach that is likely to result in a high risk to the rights and freedoms of individuals, we will notify all parties involved as well as any supervisory authorities within a reasonable timeframe. We have procedures in place to effectively detect, report and investigate these personal data breaches. 

Sensitive and private data exchange between the Site and its Users happens over a SSL secured communication channel and is encrypted and protected with digital signatures. 

**Sharing your personal information**  
We do not sell, trade, or rent Users personal identification information to others. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above.We may use third party service providers to help us operate our business and the Site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have given us your permission. 

**Expiration of personal information**  
BackerKit does not automatically expire any data that we store as a processor since personal data may be useful to users for long time periods. We have various expiration times for data on our sub-processors once the data there is no longer needed. 

**How we handle requests for data access, rectification, erasure, and data portability**  
As a Data controller, project creators can handle all of these by changing or exporting data on a backer profile page. We have also provided a tool to pseudonymise backer data for erasure requests on a backer profile page. For any other requests, contact us

**Third party websites**  
Users may find advertising or other content on our Site that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our Site. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website's own terms and policies. 

**Compliance with children's online privacy protection act**  
Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our Site from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13. 

**Changes to this privacy policy**  
BackerKit has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

**Your acceptance of these terms**  
By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes. 

**Questions?**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us. 

Updated: May 2018 

* * *
